<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 13:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The popularity of an online shop amongst consumers depends increasingly on the selection of payment methods available. At the end of an order process, customers want a selection of payment methods that they like to use and that are both simple and practical. Customers will only complete a purchase and be satisfied with their shopping [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/">Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The popularity of an online shop amongst consumers depends increasingly on the selection of payment methods available. At the end of an order process, customers want a selection of payment methods that they like to use and that are both simple and practical. Customers will only complete a purchase and be satisfied with their shopping experience when this is the case. In a survey carried out by the ECC Cologne e-commerce centre1, 42% of respondents said that they would shop with a competitor if none of their favourite payment methods were available.<span id="more-22776"></span></p>
<h2>You should keep the following five payment tips in mind at all times:</h2>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>1. Provide the optimal payment mix</strong></h3>
<p>An optimal payment mix involves offering three to five different payment methods, including online transactions, card payments and alternative payment methods. Users also prefer when all payment methods are available at a glance. </p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>2. Involve all payment parties</strong></h3>
<p>In order to offer a range of different payment methods, you should work with a payment service provider (PSP) and an acquirer. The PSP ensures that different payment solutions can be integrated smoothly in the online shop. The acquirer has a banking licence and ensures that payments (such as by credit card or giropay) can be accepted and processed. Service providers such as Wirecard offer these essential services from a single source, so only one contract is necessary.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>3. Focus on your target group</strong></h3>
<p>Business owners should understand their target groups, particularly when it comes to payment. After all, payment behaviour varies considerably. Men shop in different ways to women, and clothing is paid for differently online compared to software downloads. It is recommended to seek the advice of payment experts in this regard.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>4. Do not forget risk management</strong></h3>
<p>Misuse can be costly – for example, when shop operators are left with unpaid invoices. It is therefore advisable to work with a payment service provider who can handle both acquisition and fraud prevention services. This enables potential fraudsters to be identified before a transaction is completed.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>5. Make sure your payment page is trustworthy</strong></h3>
<p>Most people enjoy online shopping – until they reach the payment stage. Some customers have concerns when they reach the checkout stage at some less well-known online shops. The look and feel of the online shop and the payment page should therefore match and appear trustworthy and secure.</p>
<h2 style="color:black">Wirecard Checkout Seamless – integrate all relevant payment methods into your shop seamlessly!</h2>
<p>Wirecard Checkout Seamless supports all popular payment methods (credit cards, SEPA direct debit, invoices, etc.) on all PCI DSS-compliant devices. The user interface is integrated seamlessly into the online shop and looks the same for all payment methods. The payment solution is also ideal for cross-selling and upselling as goods and services can be added to the basket even after the payment details have been entered. Additionally, Wirecard Checkout Seamless features effective fraud prevention tools.</p>
<p><strong>Wirecard Checkout Seamless is already integrated into PrestaShop core software.</strong><br />
This means that merchants do not have to download and install any software – they just need to activate <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/payment-card-wallet/24188-wirecard-checkout-seamless.html" target="_blank">the free Wirecard module in PrestaShop</a> to use the payment solution.<br />
Visit Wirecard at this year’s Internet World in Munich (7–8 March 2017, hall A6, booth D214) to find out all you need to know about payments in person.</p>
<p><em>Source: ECC Cologne e-commerce centre: Payment im E-Commerce Vol. 19 – Der Internetzahlungsverkehr aus Sicht der Händler und der Verbraucher (Online payments from the perspective of merchants and consumers) http://shop.ecc-handel.de/de/Themen/Payment-Pricing/Payment-im-E-Commerce-Vol.-19- Der-Internetzahlungsverkehr-aus-Sicht-der-Haendler-und-der-Verbraucher</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/">Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 modules for optimizing sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-modules-optimizing-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-modules-optimizing-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 13:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve created a PrestaShop store and selected a popular and trustworthy payment method for customers. You&#8217;re also offering buyers delivery services that can match any profile—from the thriftiest to the most hurried—and your store&#8217;s design is adapted to your product universe. Congratulations! You&#8217;re ready to speed up sales on your online store. Check out these [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-modules-optimizing-sales/">5 modules for optimizing sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve created a PrestaShop store and selected a popular and <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/content/35-the-most-popular-online-payment-methods-by-country" target="_blank">trustworthy payment method</a> for customers. You&#8217;re also offering buyers <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/518-shipping-logistics" target="_blank">delivery services</a> that can match any profile—from the thriftiest to the most hurried—and <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/3-templates-prestashop" target="_blank">your store&#8217;s design</a> is adapted to your product universe.</p>
<p>Congratulations! You&#8217;re ready to speed up sales on your online store.</p>
<p>Check out these five tips to maximize sales with efficient and easy-to-use modules.</p>
<p><span id="more-22796"></span></p>
<h2>1.  Get your store&#8217;s name out there and increase traffic</h2>
<p>Google is no doubt the most efficient way to give your store a name, with 100 trillion queries made each month.<br />
When optimizing your site&#8217;s organic SEO, <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/price-comparison/23831-google-shopping.html" target="_blank">index your product catalog on Google Shopping</a> to be sure <b>your product visuals show up on the world&#8217;s most popular search engine</b>. In just a click, users can get to your page and you&#8217;ll pay only a cost per click for your online campaigns.</p>
<h2>2. Quickly boost average cart value</h2>
<p>Try <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/11345-push-on-cart-upselling.html" target="_blank"><b>suggesting a product when the basket summary is displayed</b></a>, just like supermarkets that place candy near the checkout counter. Don&#8217;t hesitate to slash the price to make the deal even more enticing! It&#8217;s also a great way to clear out unsold items.</p>
<h2>3. Make checkout easier</h2>
<p>Start by making account creation a breeze on your site. <b>40% of users prefer to use an existing account to check out</b>—such as Facebook, PayPal, Amazon, Google, or Twitter—rather than filling out yet another account creation form. Offering your customers the possibility of <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/8204-connect-pour-facebook-paypal-amazon-google-twitter.html" target="_blank">logging in with a social networking account</a> lets them create an account with your store in just a click, increasing conversion rates instantly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>4. Reassure visitors to convert them into customers</h2>
<p><b>Customer feedback offers two advantages: on the one hand, it puts new visitors at ease, </b>optimizing conversions, and on the other, they become rich snippets that <b>help increase your search engine visibility;</b> product satisfaction scores show up right on result pages. <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/customer-reviews/17896-store-reviews-product-reviews-google-rich-snippets.html" target="_blank">It&#8217;s a fundamental tip for increasing traffic and conversions</a>.</p>
<h2>5. Try a better way of converting &#8220;difficult&#8221; customers</h2>
<p>On average, 7 out of every 10 visitors who add items to an online cart do not make a purchase.<br />
Worry no more. Now, you can win over these potential customers using<b> </b><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/remarketing-shopping-cart-abandonment/16535-abandoned-cart-pro.html" target="_blank"><b>automatic abandoned cart reminders </b></a>that you can complement with limited-time coupons, to make deals even more tempting.</p>
<p>Last but not least, here&#8217;s one final tip: Perform a routine check-up on your own site and put yourself in the shoes of a new customer. “<i>Why should customers buy from here instead of from the competition?</i>” Make sure everything is working properly, that customer experience is smooth, that your store&#8217;s tone matches your brand universe, from its home page to your order confirmation e-mails.</p>
<p>Make a list of your main strengths (quality, service, proximity, strong brand, etc.) and remind customers of them in your communication to make yourself stand out.</p>
<p>Be sure to download <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ux-guide?utm_source=internal-linking&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=UxGuide" target="_blank">PrestaShop&#8217;s UX guide</a> to learn everything you need to know to optimize customer experience and convert visits to sales.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-modules-optimizing-sales/">5 modules for optimizing sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-modules-optimizing-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Mistakes That Make You Lose Money With Cart Abandonment</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-mistakes-make-lose-money-cart-abandonment/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-mistakes-make-lose-money-cart-abandonment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 08:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abandoned shopping carts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email remarketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retargeting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Cart abandonment costs online merchants trillions of dollars worldwide. There’s no such thing as a 0% shopping cart abandonment rate. But by applying the best practices in cart recovery, you can convert one out of four lost shoppers into sales. How? Learn from some of the most common mistakes online merchants make when trying to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-mistakes-make-lose-money-cart-abandonment/">4 Mistakes That Make You Lose Money With Cart Abandonment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cart abandonment costs online merchants trillions of dollars worldwide. There’s no such thing as a 0% shopping cart abandonment rate. But by applying the best practices in cart recovery, you can convert one out of four lost shoppers into sales. How? Learn from some of the most common mistakes online merchants make when trying to recover their lost shoppers.<span id="more-22735"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: black;"><strong>4 Mistakes That Make You Lose Money From Abandoned Carts</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">Carts Guru is a native retargeting solution for cart abandonment for PrestaShop.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em></em><br />
It’s a hard truth: Three out of four online shoppers abandon their shopping carts before completing their purchase. And yes, they’re abandoning your shopping carts. <strong>You dedicate your time and money to acquiring visitors, convincing them to shop in your store, and then poof!</strong> They leave your website.</p>
<p>Most of them never come back.</p>
<p>While there’s no such thing as a 0% shopping cart abandonment rate, <strong>it is possible to recover 20% or more of them</strong>. At <a href="https://carts.guru/" target="_blank">Carts Guru</a>, we’re experts in turning those “lost shoppers” into sales. That’s why PrestaShop has made Carts Guru a native retargeting solution for cart abandonment.</p>
<p>These are some of the most common mistakes eCommerce merchants make when dealing with abandoned shopping carts. Are you making any of them?</p>
<h3 style="color: black;"><strong>1.You’re only using email retargeting.</strong></h3>
<p>Email is one of the most important marketing channels available online. But while it’s important for you to include it in your cart recovery strategy, you shouldn’t stop there.</p>
<p>You’ll convert much more by deploying <a href="https://carts.guru/" target="_blank">a multichannel retargeting approach</a> when dealing with abandoned shopping carts.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22737" alt="Complete cart abandonment software should offer an array of retargeting options." src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/email_remarketing.png" width="1992" height="872" /><br />
With simple “If This, Then That” rules, Carts Guru goes beyond email remarketing.</p>
<p>With Carts Guru, you’ll find that a combination of email and other recovery channels will increase your ROI at a very low cost. <strong>SMS has an astonishing 97% open rate</strong>, for example. Facebook and Instagram retargeting puts your products right in front of your shoppers. And automatic calls allow you to assist customers with the shopping process and guarantee their checkout.</p>
<h3 style="color: black;"><strong>2.Your emails aren’t segmented or personalized. Be relevant.</strong></h3>
<p>Personalization and segmentation are two basic principles of online marketing:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personalization:</strong> Use all the information you have from your visitor in order to create an email that is closely related to their unique shopping experience.</li>
<li><strong>Segmentation:</strong> Classify your visitors by relevant attributes that will help you create the perfect message according to their context.</li>
</ul>
<p>These are two concepts a solution like Carts Guru can’t be without. To correctly segment your campaigns, we offer default target categories such as language, cart value and differentiation between new and old visitors. You can also create custom attributes based on your own needs.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22738" alt="An optimized retargeting campaign for shopping basket recovery should be segmented and personalized." src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/campaign.png" width="856" height="263" /></p>
<p>The best way to personalize a retargeting email is by making sure it reinforces your brand (so your visitors remember where they shopped) and includes the products your shopper added to their basket. Carts Guru’s retargeting email template allows you to add your logo, and includes the item your prospect didn’t finish purchasing at the end of the message.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22739" alt=": Your retargeting email templates should include your brand and your shopper’s product." src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/promo_code.jpg" width="500" height="565" /></p>
<h4 style="color: black;"><strong>3.You’re giving discounts too early.</strong></h4>
<p>Cart abandonment is a multifaceted issue. Shoppers can leave your online store for a number of reasons.</p>
<p>A considerable number of them just aren’t ready to finish their purchase yet. For that reason, <strong>giving them an early discount won’t really influence their final decision-making</strong>. You’ll just be losing money.</p>
<p>I usually recommend that online stores don’t retarget visitors prior to 30 minutes after they’ve opened a new shopping cart. The most effective way to start the campaign is usually a combination of an email and a SMS text message: a campaign rule that will almost surely guarantee that your user will receive the message.</p>
<p>Send discounts to the right people at the right moment. The higher the value of the cart, the longer you should wait to send a discount, especially if it’s a returning customer.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22740" alt="SMS retargeting has one of the best open rates in cart abandonment recovery." src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/supertailor.jpg" width="1024" height="829" /></p>
<p>This guarantees that only the shoppers in need of an extra incentive to purchase will lower your profit margin.</p>
<h3 style="color: black;"><strong>4.Your customers are feeling fooled.</strong></h3>
<p>A good reputation is hard to build, and very easy to lose.<br />
Your website should have every element that can convey safety to your store’s visitors. But what’s the use of including such features if shoppers end up feeling fooled by your business?</p>
<p><strong>That might be the feeling they’re left with if you’re not clear enough about all the fees they’ll be charged</strong>, for example. Presenting them only at the final stage of the checkout process might be tempting, and might convince more people to reach the last step of the conversion funnel. But it will also increase the number of shoppers who will leave your online store right before clicking the “buy” button, with the added negative experience of feeling lied to.</p>
<p><strong>Using clear language about what your online store actually offers is definitely the best long-term strategy</strong> if you want to reinforce your reputation and transform your customers into promoters of your brand.</p>
<p><strong>Can I Help You Convert Your Abandoned Carts?</strong><br />
If you avoid these mistakes and proactively work on improving your online store’s user experience, nothing will stop you from significantly reducing your cart abandonment rate.</p>
<p>I’d love to learn about your case, and I’ll be happy to help you get started with some of the best practices in the sector! How can I help you improve your shoppers’ conversion rates? Leave a comment, <a href="mailto:conrado@carts.guru">email me</a>, or chat with us at <a href="https://carts.guru/en/" target="_blank">the Carts Guru website</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/Conrado_Lamas1.png" alt="Conrado is the CMO at Carts Guru and an expert in growth, content and digital marketing." width="75" height="75" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-22767" /></p>
<div><strong>Conrado Lamas</strong><br />
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/conradolamas" target="_blank">https://www.linkedin.com/in/conradolamas</a><br />
Conrado is the CMO at Carts Guru and an expert in growth, content and digital marketing.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-mistakes-make-lose-money-cart-abandonment/">4 Mistakes That Make You Lose Money With Cart Abandonment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-mistakes-make-lose-money-cart-abandonment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Ensure Your Omni-Channel Strategy is a Success – An Interview with Faguo</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensure-omni-channel-strategy-success-interview-faguo/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensure-omni-channel-strategy-success-interview-faguo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The omni-channel strategy has become a web development cornerstone for ambitious and connected entrepreneurs. The aim is to promote sales using various distribution channels synergistically to more effectively reach a wider target base while reducing operational constraints. This is what the French company Faguo was able to achieve with international success. Currently, the company has [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensure-omni-channel-strategy-success-interview-faguo/">How to Ensure Your Omni-Channel Strategy is a Success – An Interview with Faguo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The omni-channel strategy has become a web development cornerstone for ambitious and connected entrepreneurs. The aim is to promote sales using various distribution channels synergistically to more effectively reach a wider target base while reducing operational constraints. <span id="more-22743"></span></p>
<p>This is what the French company Faguo was able to achieve with international success. Currently, the company has a network of physical stores along with an online presence thanks to its e-commerce website and social networks, which helps advertise their business and distribute in France and across 24 countries.</p>
<p>In this video, Faguo&#8217;s co-founder Nicolas and the brand&#8217;s e-commerce manager Anne-Charlotte explain how this omni-channel strategy was designed and share their advice for successfully developing your business.</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lOf5uMyGcIg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=faguo">Watch more vidéo</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensure-omni-channel-strategy-success-interview-faguo/">How to Ensure Your Omni-Channel Strategy is a Success – An Interview with Faguo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ensure-omni-channel-strategy-success-interview-faguo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social marketing and smartphones — trends you should know if you’re working in fashion</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-marketing-smartphones-trends-know-youre-working-fashion/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-marketing-smartphones-trends-know-youre-working-fashion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 17:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eva Lacalle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22730</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Smartphone use is on the rise. Whether they&#8217;re keeping up-to-date on social networks, searching online, watching videos, or making purchases, users increasingly prefer to use a smartphone. This has resulted in a change in buyer–seller mentality that is better adapted to new behaviors smartphone technology has set in motion. Social networks and widespread purchasing from [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-marketing-smartphones-trends-know-youre-working-fashion/">Social marketing and smartphones — trends you should know if you’re working in fashion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Smartphone use is on the rise.</strong> Whether they&#8217;re keeping up-to-date on social networks, searching online, watching videos, or making purchases, users increasingly prefer to use a smartphone. This has resulted in <strong>a change in buyer–seller mentality that is better adapted to new behaviors</strong> smartphone technology has set in motion.<span id="more-22730"></span></p>
<p>Social networks and widespread purchasing from mobile devices have been key factors in this behavioral change. And while social marketing and m-commerce are the latest trends in the online world right now, <strong>these concepts are even more prevalent in the fashion world</strong>, one of the top sectors in e-commerce.</p>
<p>In fact, <strong>the fashion sector is among the most advanced in terms of marketing techniques on social networks and mobile devices</strong>. If this is your sector, here are some of the trends you can incorporate into your marketing strategy, as well as some basic errors to avoid.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ff1378">Create a communication channel between social networks and your brand</h4>
<p>There are quite a few fashion names obsessed with forming a big community on social networks. But when they finally have one, they often don&#8217;t use it for the one main goal of any e-commerce, which is selling products. Sure, we&#8217;ll all make this error once or twice: post something on social networks, use the perfect hashtags and finally, <strong>forget to add a link to the product page</strong>.</p>
<p>It should be remembered that most users of any social network are on their phone, and product searches from a smartphone are not as simple as from a computer. So make things easy! <strong>What&#8217;s the point of having a big community if no followers actually visit your store?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s true that several social networks such as Instagram don&#8217;t make this easy, but other options are available that do, so choose wisely. Be mindful that <strong>to avoid lengthy URLs</strong>, you can use either a URL shortener or preview content offered by sites like Facebook.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ff1378">Choose the right image size</h4>
<p><strong>Image size</strong> is another common mistake, <strong>both in terms of responsive design as well as on social networks</strong>. Sure, if you make any changes to an online store or a social networking page, you most likely do it from a computer. Just be sure to think about the device a consumer might view the content on.</p>
<p>For responsive design, observe how your template displays images on a mobile device screen and adapt your images accordingly. As for posts on social networks, note the image size they use, then simply take images from your website and adapt them to correctly match the metrics of each social network. <strong>In fashion, images are a fundamental part of sales, so make sure they&#8217;re impeccable!</strong></p>
<h4 style="color:#ff1378">Humanize your brand</h4>
<p>One of the biggest mistakes brands make is turning their social networking pages into a <strong>self-promotion channel</strong>. The page ends up looking like an infomercial, and it&#8217;s no secret how low expectations are for call-in TV shopping&#8230; </p>
<p>For example, if you are selling for your own brand, tell customers about who you are and how you work. Teach them about your history, your team, the people behind your products. Let your page be a window for consumers to the inner workings of your team.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ff1378">Try out the latest social networks</h4>
<p>(Almost) all fashion stores have accepted that social networks are an essential part of the online world, but most prefer to keep things simple and just use Facebook.</p>
<p>These stores haven&#8217;t caught on yet that <strong>new social networking services</strong> are a boon for online fashion stores. Since these new services are <strong>very visual in nature</strong>, they&#8217;re perfect for sectors like fashion where &#8220;image&#8221; is everything. Instagram, Snapchat, and the not-so-new YouTube are definitely alternatives to be considered if your e-commerce is connected to the fashion sector.<!--more--></p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, <strong>they make fantastic channels for humanizing brands or reaching out to potential customers</strong> who are just within reach, particularly those seeking less text and more image.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ff1378">Give video a shot</h4>
<p>For several years now, online fashion stores have been realizing that sales go up when garments are shown both on a model and before a background. Nowadays, it&#8217;s safe to say using a picture and a video is sure to turn some heads.</p>
<p>First of all, it&#8217;s because <strong>seeing a garment in a still image is nothing like seeing it in motion</strong>. The drape and cut of clothing or its color during lighting changes are aspects it wasn&#8217;t possible to depict in a still image. Videos have changed that. They&#8217;re a nice way around the biggest obstacle in online commerce: not being able to touch the things you buy. Videos have an effect on customers that no other audiovisual format can provide.</p>
<p>Second of all, they&#8217;re <strong>the perfect content to share on social networks</strong>. This is true because they increase the visibility of posts (and, in turn, of products too). Think about your own behavior on social networks: you probably hit play yourself when you see a video, right? Lastly, it&#8217;s easy for videos to go viral. Just ask the guys working on recipes at Tasty!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-marketing-smartphones-trends-know-youre-working-fashion/">Social marketing and smartphones — trends you should know if you’re working in fashion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-marketing-smartphones-trends-know-youre-working-fashion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Eugen, Ambassador of the month &#124; January 2017</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-eugen-ambassador-month-january-2017/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-eugen-ambassador-month-january-2017/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[floreravaud]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Ambassadors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22707</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Eugen is a PrestaShop merchant and our Ambassador in Düsseldorf, Germany. He has organized no fewer than 5 meetups in 2016! He loves meeting regularly with the community to talk about best practices and to enjoy a good time with other PrestaShop enthusiasts. We chose him as Ambassador of the month to reward his exemplarity [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-eugen-ambassador-month-january-2017/">Meet Eugen, Ambassador of the month | January 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eugen is a PrestaShop merchant and our Ambassador in Düsseldorf, Germany. He has organized no fewer than 5 meetups in 2016! He loves meeting regularly with the community to talk about best practices and to enjoy a good time with other PrestaShop enthusiasts. We chose him as Ambassador of the month to reward his exemplarity and asked him our usual questions for you to better know him.<span id="more-22707"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About you</h2>
<p><strong>Three words to best describe you:</strong><br />
Networker, lucky duck, creative.</p>
<p><strong>If you were to write a book about yourself, what would you name it?</strong><br />
The best way to make no career &#8211; the first ten years of my professional life.</p>
<p><strong>What is your hidden talent?</strong><br />
I like to bake cakes and tarts. They are quite successful!</p>
<p><strong>If you could travel anywhere right now, where would you go and why?</strong><br />
I would fly to a sunny country with a beach. Germany is so rainy in winter <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About your country</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite local food or drink?</strong><br />
If I have guests from abroad they always want to eat <em>Schweinehaxe</em> (pork hock) and drink <em>Altbier</em> (dark beer from Düsseldorf), and I enjoy eating it myself.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/ambassador_january.jpg" alt="ambassador_january" width="1138" height="751" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22709" /></p>
<p style="text-align:center"><em>Schweinehaxe | Credits: Erik Forsberg</em></p>
<p><strong>Give us a fun fact about your city, Düsseldorf:</strong><br />
Once a year, the city transforms into a great circus for “<em>Düsseldorfer Karneval</em>”. People dress up with costumes, listen to live music and drink beer. I particularly like this carnival because you get to wear anything you want and nobody will judge you <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About PrestaShop</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite PrestaShop store?</strong><br />
Of course my company’s: www.eikora.de <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" class="wp-smiley" />  Also, there are numerous beautiful shops created on PrestaShop. These include, for example, www.urbanara.de and www.leslipfrancais.de</p>
<p><strong>What opportunities does PrestaShop provide in your country?</strong><br />
PrestaShop is becoming <strong>more and more popular in Germany</strong> and the community is constantly growing. This is nice because it is now easier to exchange on local topics. I hope I will soon welcome new PrestaShop Ambassadors in Germany.</p>
<p><em>Interested in becoming a PrestaShop Ambassador? <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/application-form" target="_blank">Apply now <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </a></em></p>
<p><strong>What is your feedback on the new major version, PrestaShop 1.7?</strong><br />
My first impression is very good. I love the new template solution! It has become so easy to develop customer-specific design, I hope to be able to implement the first project with the new version soon.</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About being an Ambassador</h2>
<p><strong>What is your proudest moment as a PrestaShop Ambassador?</strong><br />
I love networking, and organizing meetups allows me to do so. I especially like when at the end of a meetup community members come to me saying they have learned something thanks to my presentation. It makes it really rewarding! I am looking forward to meeting new people and broaching other topics. </p>
<p><strong>What do you like the most about being an Ambassador?</strong><br />
The best thing about being a PrestaShop Ambassador is that I constantly learn new things to show later on in the Meetup. There is always something new going on, that’s what makes it so fun for me but also for participants. </p>
<p><strong>A last word?</strong><br />
I would like to thank <strong>Hagen Meischner</strong>, PrestaShop Country Manager in Germany. He always stands by me with advice, and our phone calls and meetings are always very creative and inspiring. I am pleased to represent PrestaShop in Germany with Hagen.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you very much Eugen!</strong></p>
<p>Find out more about <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/ambassador/eugen-kuschnir" target="_blank">Eugen’s profile</a> and <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Dusseldorf-PrestaShop-Meetup/" target="_blank">join his meetup group</a>.<br />
Do you want to become a PrestaShop Ambassador? <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/application-form" target="_blank">Apply now</a>.</p>
<p>See you next month <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-eugen-ambassador-month-january-2017/">Meet Eugen, Ambassador of the month | January 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-eugen-ambassador-month-january-2017/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why customer care is of (utmost) importance to e-commerce</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/customer-care-utmost-importance-e-commerce/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/customer-care-utmost-importance-e-commerce/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 07:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eva Lacalle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22669</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Customer care is a key sales service for any type of retail channel. But in the online world, customer loyalty is what increases a store&#8217;s presence. According to recent studies, up to 65% of customers gave up on a purchase at the checkout page because of lingering doubts about the company and/or their products. This [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/customer-care-utmost-importance-e-commerce/">Why customer care is of (utmost) importance to e-commerce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Customer care is a <strong>key sales service</strong> for any type of retail channel. But in the online world, <strong>customer loyalty</strong> is what increases a store&#8217;s presence. According to recent studies, up to 65% of customers gave up on a purchase at the checkout page because of lingering doubts about the company and/or their products.</p>
<p>This is common among more conventional shoppers who have had to contend with buying online rather than in brick-and-mortar stores. Unlike at a cash register, they have no one to speak with about their doubts. That said, if you consider <strong>the number of users closing their window with a full cart,</strong> an <strong>overwhelming majority are willing to spend more online</strong> if they get the attention they need. It’s time to give it to them. <span id="more-22669"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #23135a;"><strong>What is the current state of customer care?</strong></h2>
<p>Information during the checkout process, troubleshooting, and post-sale customer service are three of the most important aspects of customer care. The most common techniques used by online stores are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>E-mail support or contact forms</strong>, used by 90% of companies.</li>
<li><strong>Telephone hotlines</strong>, used by more than 80% of companies.</li>
<li>Apart from <strong>FAQs</strong>, which are offered by two-thirds of all stores, hotlines are the method of choice for customer care in Spain.</li>
<li><strong>Live chat</strong> is implemented by 20% of online stores.</li>
<li>Although <strong>forums</strong> have become largely anecdotal in some countries, in Spain they are the preferred method for e-commerce.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #23135a;"><strong>Why is this so important?</strong></h2>
<p>Stores have only one chance to make a first impression—and in the online world, this is paramount. Since <strong>customers will be on guard following a negative experience</strong>, large sums are at stake.</p>
<p>In addition, after a negative experience, it has been shown that between 10 and 12 positive experiences are necessary in order to win back a positive impression of a store. <strong>Not all users are willing to give a second chance</strong>.</p>
<p>Worse yet, <strong>it&#8217;s rare for the same customer to visit your store again following a negative experience</strong>. This is particularly true if your sector deals in luxury products, as customers require a more tailored approach.</p>
<h2 style="color: #23135a;"><strong>So what happens after a bad experience?</strong></h2>
<p><em>What happens if I&#8217;ve already made a mistake? Should I just cut my losses for that buyer? Let&#8217;s be clear: you should always take bad experiences seriously.</em></p>
<p>The first thing you should try to do is <strong>learn what problem the user actually encountered</strong>. There are parts of your online store that you can automate. Others, like customer service, should be adapted to each individual problem, whether it&#8217;s a request for product information or a problem with delivery.</p>
<p>Another thing to take into account is <strong>response speed</strong>. When faced with a customer issue, it&#8217;s important to reach out as quickly as possible so the customer sees that you care. If you&#8217;ve opted for a communication channel such as e-mail or a contact form, respond within a short time frame and, if you can, provide other communication methods that offer an instantaneous response, such as phone or online chat.</p>
<p>Finally, depending on the problem, think about <strong>ways you could compensate your customer for the bad experience</strong>. People generally understand that mistakes happen, but if users feel that they are looked after and compensated when it happens to them, it&#8217;s easy to make up for a bad experience&#8211;so long as you act quickly.</p>
<p>In addition, we encourage you to <strong>follow up on the problem</strong> to be sure that the customer is satisfied with the result. Following up isn&#8217;t only about learning whether or not the problem was resolved. It&#8217;s also an opportunity to have a dialogue with the user in a positive atmosphere where the customer will feel cared for until the very end.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that studies show a satisfied client will recommend your store to between four and six people, whereas an unhappy customer will vent to between nine and fifteen.</p>
<h2 style="color: #23135a;"><strong>What are the most common problems?</strong></h2>
<p>We suggest you take special note of these ways to prevent the following problems with customer care.</p>
<h4 style="color: #23135a;">Unprepared staff</h4>
<p>One of the biggest mistakes is not having experts available to assist customers. If you are lacking in this area, <strong>organize a team</strong> composed of <strong>individuals specialized in</strong> product information, troubleshooting, etc. It&#8217;s also important that this team be <strong>empathetic</strong>, so that they are capable of reaching out to customers.</p>
<p>Finally, be sure to offer them the <strong>means necessary to solve problems</strong>. By this, we don&#8217;t just mean technical means, but also the know-how required to make decisions.</p>
<h4 style="color: #23135a;">Unable to meet order volume</h4>
<p>This happens to quite a few companies during specific periods like Christmas. In short, <strong>high order volume exceeds their capacity</strong>. During times like this, poor planning can lead to disaster. Be sure to anticipate order growth and consider hiring extra hands to help you manage it.</p>
<h4 style="color: #23135a;">No action plan to respond to complaints</h4>
<p>Nobody wants to deal with an unhappy customer, and many might even freeze up in such a situation. Come up with an <strong>action plan to guide your employees in matters of customer care</strong>, so they can know how to react to the most common situations. This can be particularly useful for new hires.</p>
<h4 style="color: #23135a;">Third-party mistakes</h4>
<p>Sometimes, mistakes can come about with services rendered by a provider or shipping company. You should explain the problem to your customer, and <strong>in no case should you ignore it</strong>. Although your store is not directly responsible for the mistake, it is your job to make sure it doesn&#8217;t happen again—so in this way, you are involved. Above all, be sure to let your customer know that you are addressing the issue and trying to find a suitable solution.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/customer-care-utmost-importance-e-commerce/">Why customer care is of (utmost) importance to e-commerce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/customer-care-utmost-importance-e-commerce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>15 Reasons to Sell Online with PrestaShop</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-reasons-sell-online-prestashop/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-reasons-sell-online-prestashop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 06:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Fernandes]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Keep Calm and Sell Online with PrestaShop. Selling online with PrestaShop is about letting sellers push their limits, taking advantage of everything the web has to offer them. In any event, that&#8217;s the challenge PrestaShop set for itself nearly ten years ago. With our simple, efficient, powerful, and international solution, your product, idea, project, store, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-reasons-sell-online-prestashop/">15 Reasons to Sell Online with PrestaShop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keep Calm and <strong>Sell Online with PrestaShop</strong>. Selling online with PrestaShop is about letting sellers push their limits, taking advantage of everything the web has to offer them. In any event, that&#8217;s the challenge PrestaShop set for itself nearly ten years ago.<span id="more-22686"></span></p>
<p>With our simple, efficient, powerful, and international solution, your product, idea, project, store, or start-up is ready to become the next big <strong>e-commerce</strong> in the regions you decide to enter. The sun never sets on the PrestaShop ecosystem, a true asset for merchants in France and around the world who are looking to reap the benefits of web-development potential in Europe and elsewhere!</p>
<p>Want to know just what the last ten years have been all about? We&#8217;ve chosen 15 examples below—just to name a few—from open-source development to collaboration with a group of experts dedicated to helping passionate, ambitious merchants the world over.</p>
<h2>15 Reasons to Sell Online with PrestaShop:</h2>
<p>1. It&#8217;s about ranking among unstoppable French start-ups, like Sessun, Bobbies, and Monsieur Moustache.</p>
<p>2. It&#8217;s about easy-to-use software that&#8217;s also accessible, and a user-friendly interface that welcomes both newbies and coders, from the keyboard jockey to the web novice.</p>
<p>3. It&#8217;s about a unique program used by such renowned retailers as Eric Bompard, Manoush, and Ba&amp;sh.</p>
<p>4. It&#8217;s about having a hub that connects an ecosystem of digital commerce experts (developers, e-commerce bosses, project managers), both in France and abroad.</p>
<p>5. It&#8217;s about joining a community with more than a million members in over 195 countries, all of which are rooting for ambitious entrepreneurs hoping to pursue their dreams worldwide.</p>
<p>6. It&#8217;s about having a free app that includes more than 500 functionalities, letting you manage your catalogue, orders and customers as you sell products on a responsive mobile site. The goal: grow your sales activity online and in-store.</p>
<p>7. It&#8217;s about a scalable solution that lets you quickly develop a store for the European market and the rest of the world in just a few clicks.</p>
<p>8. It&#8217;s about having the blessing of 250,000 active e-commerce sites around the world.</p>
<p>9. It&#8217;s about selling organic soap in Normandy, Pokémon cards in Japan, sports equipment in the Democratic Republic of Congo, natural beauty products in Malaysia, and T-shirts in Colombia.</p>
<p>10. It&#8217;s about trying 5,000 modules and themes available on the <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/">Marketplace</a>, which ensure that you have the elements you need throughout all of your online store development phases.</p>
<p>11. It&#8217;s about using an accessible and versatile open-source solution that offers high flexibility and development transparency, at just half the development costs of other open-source solutions on the market.</p>
<p>12. It&#8217;s about Pure-Players, the heroes of the digital world, who achieved success with the help of PrestaShop: Le Slip Français, Décathlon, Envie de Fraises, Private Sport Shop, Brico-Privé, and many more.</p>
<p>13. It&#8217;s about having specialized hosting services that let you handle your site&#8217;s performance, even with high data volume.</p>
<p>14. It&#8217;s about e-commerce sites that work, and that generate tens of millions of euros in revenue through very different sales models (direct sale, private sale, marketplaces, social media).</p>
<p>15. It&#8217;s about an ultra-motivated, on-the-ground team with high standards, looking to make your store the next e-commerce success story.</p>
<p>To find out more, get in touch with our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">partner agencies</a> or go ahead and <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/download">download </a>the PrestaShop software.</p>
<p><strong>Happy e-commerce New Year to all!</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-reasons-sell-online-prestashop/">15 Reasons to Sell Online with PrestaShop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-reasons-sell-online-prestashop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 traps to avoid to optimize the UX of your Ecommerce site</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-traps-to-avoid-to-optimize-the-ux-of-your-ecommerce-site/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-traps-to-avoid-to-optimize-the-ux-of-your-ecommerce-site/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 09:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22698</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Everyone in e-commerce is talking about user experience, but it&#8217;s hard to grasp what this term really means, and even harder to optimize it to the point of boosting conversion rates on your online store. So what exactly is user experience? Often called UX, user experience refers to the path users take on your site [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-traps-to-avoid-to-optimize-the-ux-of-your-ecommerce-site/">3 traps to avoid to optimize the UX of your Ecommerce site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone in e-commerce is talking about user experience, but it&#8217;s hard to grasp what this term really means, and even harder to optimize it to the point of boosting conversion rates on your online store. </p>
<p>So what exactly is user experience? Often called UX, user experience refers to the path users take on your site before making a purchase, when they&#8217;re still just prospects. <span id="more-22698"></span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s crucial to offer them the best user experience possible so they&#8217;ll stay on your site, maximizing your chances of increasing conversions. </p>
<p>Even if you yourself are a regular e-commerce buyer and you know your offering backwards and forwards, you&#8217;ll need to steer clear of some traps to ensure user experience is optimized on your site. </p>
<p>PrestaShop UX designer <a href="https://fr.linkedin.com/in/leadesign" target="_blank">Léa Mendès</a> explains how to avoid three common pitfalls, ensuring your user experience is one to remember! </p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lr0ekGR_Je4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&#038;utm_medium=article&#038;utm_campaign=youtube&#038;utm_content=uxprestashop"> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-traps-to-avoid-to-optimize-the-ux-of-your-ecommerce-site/">3 traps to avoid to optimize the UX of your Ecommerce site</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-traps-to-avoid-to-optimize-the-ux-of-your-ecommerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>UX Design — the top design mistakes and how to fix them</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ux-design-top-design-mistakes-fix/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ux-design-top-design-mistakes-fix/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 07:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eva Lacalle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>On the PrestaShop blog, we have already given advice for improving user experience, like this article explaining how to boost conversions. Now we&#8217;re back again to talk about UX and offer some tips for improving design. The thing is, there are a number of mistakes designers make very often that can detract from an online [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ux-design-top-design-mistakes-fix/">UX Design — the top design mistakes and how to fix them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the PrestaShop blog, we have already given advice for <strong>improving user experience</strong>, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-user-experience-boost-conversions/">like this article explaining how to boost conversions</a>. Now we&#8217;re back again to talk about UX and offer some tips for improving design. The thing is, there are a number of mistakes designers make very often that can detract from an online store&#8217;s quality.<span id="more-22634"></span></p>
<p>Creating a superior UX requires considering all the <strong>design factors and elements that visitors to the site will be interacting with.</strong> User experience is affected by <strong>design</strong>—usability, accessibility, graphic design&#8230;the list goes on. But just as important are <strong>psychological considerations</strong> such as the emotions users might feel when coming into contact with your brand or products.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go through some of the most common design-related mistakes that are likely to come up during any project. These mistakes are frequently present in the interface when personal information needs to be entered or when the user is presented with a set of options. In both cases, design is a key factor in achieving a website that&#8217;s both aesthetic and user-friendly.</p>
<p>More specifically, we&#8217;ll be delving into <strong>recurrent mistakes in form design</strong>, since this is vital to any online store in a world where users have no issue closing a page with a full shopping cart. There are certainly exceptions to the rules we&#8217;ll be listing here. Consider it a handy little guide to help you improve your store&#8217;s design.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">One-column form lists</h2>
<p>Users usually prefer to read questionnaires from top to bottom, so when they&#8217;re faced with a myriad of boxes to fill out, it&#8217;s best if lists show up in <strong>one column</strong> rather than many.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/1.jpg" alt="1" width="1000" height="402" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22635" /></p>
<p>Another option is <strong>grouping form elements together by information type</strong> and presenting them separately. That means one column for personal data, another for payment information, and another for delivery. To improve user interaction, the information you ask for within each of these categories should always be in just one column.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Place labels at the top of forms</h2>
<p>Forms are filled out more quickly when labels are shown <strong>above the form or section</strong> instead of on the left-hand side. Nonetheless, there is a very clear exception to this rule. For big lists with multiple choice fields, it&#8217;s best to place labels to the left. This helps reduce the total height of the form and makes reading easier by giving more importance to labels, thus improving usability.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/2.jpg" alt="2" width="1000" height="429" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22636" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Grouping labels with their input box</h2>
<p>Leaving exactly the same distance between options and their labels could confuse users.<br />
<strong>Group together labels</strong> to make it clear which box goes with which information at a mere glance.</p>
<p>This is a crucial step when there are lots of fields. Otherwise, users could end up losing track of which field goes with which label.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/3.jpg" alt="3" width="1000" height="429" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22637" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Don&#8217;t use capital letters</h2>
<p>Seriously, capital letters <strong>have got to go</strong>. Firstly, in the digital world, capital letters are equivalent to yelling, and no customer wants to be yelled at. Secondly, they are quite simply harder to read. On the other hand, barring specific styles which should be uniform across the entire page, never write only in lower case.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/4.jpg" alt="4" width="1000" height="429" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22638" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Don&#8217;t use input boxes as labels</h2>
<p>The space saving factor is likely the only reason designers keep doing this in the first place. Although it was common practice back in the day, the truth is that it ends up <strong>causing usability problems</strong>.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/5.jpg" alt="5" width="1000" height="429" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22639" /></p>
<p>Once users click in the box, the label information disappears. If they click on something else, it&#8217;s easy to forget what they needed to put in it when they come back. They also can&#8217;t check to make sure everything was typed in correctly before they confirm their purchase or that the system detects no errors. It&#8217;s also difficult to visualize the fields to fill out when scrolling through.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Specify where entry errors are located</h2>
<p>When users make a mistake while filling out a form, <strong>indicate exactly where the error is located</strong>. If possible, <strong>indicate its nature</strong>, too. This is even more important for longer forms, since an error that can&#8217;t be located could cause a user to close the page. Use this method to greatly improve interaction with the user.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/6.jpg" alt="6" width="1000" height="362" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22640" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Keep basic help in plain view</h2>
<p>There are times when <strong>basic help for users filling out your questionnaire</strong> can come in handy. If you&#8217;ve made it available, keep it in plain view. After all, the point is to help the user finish as quickly as possible.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/7.jpg" alt="7" width="1000" height="362" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22641" /></p>
<p>Whichever way you choose to do this, users just might enter a password incorrectly, or they could enter too few characters. In any case, if an error pops up, users should be able to locate it, hover over a (?) symbol, find out that it needs to be five characters or more, and fix the problem. It&#8217;s infinitely easier if you explain it. It&#8217;s one more way to offer a simple, user-friendly experience.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Highlight call-to-action buttons</h2>
<p>If you offer two options, <strong>highlight the call-to-action (CTA) that will generate the most interest</strong>. To do this, you can opt for a larger size or a color that pops. The goal is to direct user attention. If you don&#8217;t think that the second option is useful, simply eliminate it. Not only does this improve user experience, making it easier for the customer to choose the more logical option, but it also enables designers to highlight the CTAs that are more beneficial to them.<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/8.jpg" alt="8" width="1000" height="362" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22642" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b">Get rid of anything unnecessary</h2>
<p>Quite frankly, site owners often ask for data that isn&#8217;t truly necessary during checkout and customers who fill out never-ending forms tend to call it quits. The buying experience can sometimes be so slow and boring that users don&#8217;t buy anything from the store, despite being happy with the product.</p>
<p>Think about what&#8217;s absolutely necessary, what&#8217;s optional, and finally, what you could do without. Nobody wants to spend half the day filling out information just to make a purchase, so <strong>keep things as simple and as fun as possible</strong>. User experience will improve and you will see your conversion ratios follow suit!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ux-design-top-design-mistakes-fix/">UX Design — the top design mistakes and how to fix them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ux-design-top-design-mistakes-fix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
